

Michel de Graaf michel@re-invention.nl http://re-invention.nl +31 (0) 6 36 42 74 07

Michel de Graaf Software Engineer

About me: Fullstack software engineer with over 15 years of experience shipping complex software solutions.

My strength lies in architecting and developing new products from concept to production (MVP) or upgrading existing projects to the latest development stack in the cloud with professional software engineering practices such as Automated Testing (BDD/TDD), Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery and Infrastructure Monitoring with a pragmatic eye on scaling your architecture for future growth.

- Specialised in architecting and developing advanced web applications and web services (REST, Graphql).
- Integrating different software systems with each other and managing data flows (REST, SOAP, Graphql)
- Developing advanced user interfaces using Javascript (ES6, Typescript, React, React-native, Flux, Redux, Elm, Apollo) on the web and mobile devices.
- Scaling and deploying applications in the cloud (AWS, ECS, Docker, Elastic beanstalk).
- Setting up a professional software engineering pipeline (Continuous Integration, Continuous Delivery).
- Strong interest and knowledge of computer security (Fuzzing, Pentesting) and Linux ninja.

My approach to software craftsmanship is test driven (TDD), agile and using the best tool for the job. I favour a SCRUM/Agile driven project and have experience in managing projects using this methodology.

Experience

2004 - Current, Re-invention (Founder)

My consultancy company: specialised in advanced (web-based) software solutions

2016 - 2019, BEEQUIP - Interim CTO / Fullstack developer (Freelancer)

Developing BEEQUIP's (startup, fintech) online leasing platform from the ground up. Designed and implemented an information system (BEEHIVE) where we managed to capture the business processes and automated many of them. This system exposed a graphQL API used by BEEQUIP's broker portal and customer portal. My best work to date as this was mainly a solo effort for 2 years. In 2018 this system processed 240 milion leases in production. Tech used: Ruby on Rails / Python / / TypeScript / Javascript / node.js / React / Apollo / Salesforce / Dynamics NAV, GraphQL, Docker, AWS, Continuous integration, Continuous delivery

2015 - 2018, Backpackapp - CTO

Building an Travel agency platform for backpackers on the go, the challenge here lies in automated document classification and recognition. This project consists out of a native mobile app and a web application. Tech used: Ruby, Rails, React native, Javascript (ES6)

2015 - 2016, Tele2 - Software Engineer (Freelancer)

Maintaining a software system used to commission and provision (4g) network devices. Developed consistency checking tool to audit network device configurations. Advance overall software quality by improving tests / software engineering practices. Tech used: Ruby, Rails, EventMachine, RabbitMQ, Backbone.js, MongoDB, Redis, Javascript, Docker.

2014 - 2016, Postinitial - CTO

Building an e-learning platform for Corporate Finance. Tech used: Ruby, Javascript, Rails, React.js, Flux, Docker

2008 - 2015, Kabisa, Software Engineer / lead / Devops / Consulatant

Kabisa is specialised in developing elegant (enterprise) software solutions using technologies such as Ruby(on Rails) and Java. I have been with Kabisa since the start and have grown in to several roles such as: scrum master, DevOps, lead developer, consultant and software architect on a wide range of interesting projects for customers such as: Philips, ViaViela B.V., Media Groep Limburg, Seacon Logistics, TMC and Yellobrick.

2007 - 2008, Philips

Internship where I developed an internet connected television prototype where users can share photos and play games over the internet.

Education

2008 - 2009, University of Amsterdam Master (MSc), Software engineering For my master thesis I researched Intelligent fuzzing of web-applications.

2005 - 2008, Avans Hogeschool s-Hertogenbosch

- Graduated cum laude
- Graduation internship at the Philips Innovation Lab, worked on the European funded Amigo project (http://www.hitech-projects.com/euprojects/amigo/)

Skills

Languages Dutch (mother tongue)English (fluent)

German (basic)

Programming Languages

o Ruby	Rust	CSS
 Javascript / Typescript 	Python	o (X)HTML
/ Flow / Node	 Elixir 	o SQL
∘ C++	 Golang 	 LaTex
o Java	o Elm	

Experience with frameworks/libraries

 Ruby on Rails 	 Next.js / Express.js
o Sinatra	 Apache Camel
 Rhomobile 	Chef
 Backbone.js 	 Metasploit
o React / Redux / Apollo	

Software/Services

 Linux (Debian/Ubuntu) 	 Docker
Git / Subversion	 Jenkens CI
Mac OSX	 Gitlab

Adobe PhotoshopPostgreSQL / MySQL

Adobe IllustratorAmazon EC2MongoDBRabbitMQ

Additional Honors & Awards & Certificates

- o Graduated cum laude for bachelor degree computer science
- o Professional Scrum Master certificate (Scrum.org)
- o Coursera: Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- Placed first at the RubyenRails 2009 rumble (http://2009.rubyenrails.nl/)